Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. This is for
coaches, mentors, trainers, and service
providers to grow and accomplish more
than they ever imagined to make more
money in their businesses. Now, today I
have a topic that I want to talk with
you about. It's one key area where I
know is going to have the biggest impact
for my coaches, mentors, trainers, and
service providers. And it's related to
working with my coaching clients, what I
believe is one of the single greatest
areas that will impact them. Now
understand this is coming from a
business coaching perspective. I am a
business coach. I'm not a life coach.
I'm not a therapist. And so some of what
I might say may conflict with what is
taught in fields of life coaching and
therapy. But understand that if you want
to build a business. These are key.
These are important to understand. and
you got to operate differently as a
business owner than you may in those
other types of modalities. So, I just
want to kind of get that out of the way.
There's a great teacher that's out
there. His name is uh Jaco Willink. He
has a video on YouTube and I'm going to
get to his video in a second, but I want
to I want to talk about
when things don't go how you want them
to, when things fail, when you're
struggling, when you feel at your wits
end, when bad situations happen,
turning them into blessings immediately,
not waiting for the outcome to change,
not waiting for the situation to change.
This isn't emotional bypassing or
anything like that. It's literally one
of the most timeless arts that is out
there. And there's a great book called
The Obstacle is the Way. It's written by
Ryan Holidayiday. It's based on uh the
writings of the book Meditations of
Marcus Aurelius,
uh the Gregory Hayes translation right
here. One of my favorite books
that's out there. And it's based on uh
stoicism, which is not a lot of people
think it's bypassing your emotions. It's
not feeling anything. That's not true.
Uh in my experience, it has more to do
with being able to feel the emotion but
not letting it affect you.
being able to live a much more vibrant
life um and not letting things not going
your way turn into struggle.
Turning adversity into your number one
advantage.
And that's what I want to talk about in
this
episode here today. Now, there's a great
video again I want to I want to just
show you this. It's uh it's by Jaco
Willink. He's a US Navy Seal and he
talks about this. Just watch the video.
Go check it out.
Let's check it out.
>> One of my direct subordinates, one of my
guys that worked for me, he would he
would call me up or pull me aside with
some major problem, some issue that was
going on, and he'd say, "Boss, we got
this and that and the other thing." And
I'd look at him and I'd say, "Good."
And finally one day, he was telling me
about some issue that he was having,
some problem. And he said, "I already
know what you're going to say." I said,
"Well, what am I going to say?" He said,
"You're going to say good."
[Music]
Listen, that's one of my favorite videos
that's out there simply because
I think that the ability to
say that's a good situation no matter
what is happening will shift how you
look at everything. Saying, "What can I
learn from this?" this. And there's a
lesson from a podcast with uh Ed Milelet
and
Shawn White from about six years ago. Ed
Milelet and Shawn White where they talk
about how Shawn
>> One more
>> Shawn lost
and he says, this is the title of the
podcast. I'm happy I lost. I wouldn't
have the gold medal if I won. Now, you
might you might think, okay, that's this
that's this podcast episode right here.
You might think that how can you find
joy and happiness in in losing and
things not going how you want them to?
Well, that's a peak performance uh shift
that again I think is very important.
I'm not talking about grinding. I'm not
talking about burning yourself out. I'm
not talking about not feeling or
bypassing your emotions. I'm talking
about strengthening yourself and
flipping your perspective
to where no matter what happens in your
life, no matter how bad a situation
feels,
you can get back up again and you can be
stronger because of it and you can learn
from it. In the moment it might feel so
hard, so difficult,
but realizing that this is temporary
and saying, you know what? What's the
blessing in this situation?
I've been having lots of situations in
my life that have happened. I pray I've
prayed for strength in this. And of
course, the Lord brings in situations
where, you know, not that he caused
them, but like there's situations where
I can grow. And he's literally saying,
"Here's one you can grow in.
And I can tell you as I come through
this, like I I don't want to go through,
you know, my list of woes, but
learning to grow and strengthen myself
in my business, my ability to think, my
ability to operate and find the good in
every situation is powerful. Now, what I
like to do is this. Listen, you're going
to feel crappy sometimes. You're going
to have situations go not how you want
them to. What you want to do is give
yourself a temporary moment to feel it
and then learn to find emotional
regulation, joy, and happiness.
Don't sit in it. And that's one of the
things. And we might find comfort in sit
sitting in it for a long period of time.
That might be something that we're used
to doing. But I want you to change
your normal
mode of operation
where you just sit in your pain and keep
replaying it over and over again. You
need to realize that you are in charge
of your state of mind and your state of
body and how you feel. And this is one
of the things that I think
listen stuff happens doesn't go how you
want. You will have all the emotions
come up and they feel like they're going
to break you.
And then you take a moment. It might be
an hour from now. It might be a few days
from now.
But I would encourage you as a business
owner, listen, I used to give myself
days and days and days to recover. And I
and I found myself I couldn't be
productive. So I've gotten to the point
now where it's like, okay, 15 minutes.
I can feel it for 15 minutes and I can
immediately
snap back into where I need to be.
And this is something that I've always
I've been praying for the ability to do.
And it's something that I I believe has
just impacted my life. Things are not
always going to go how we want them to.
That's just not reality on planet Earth.
But if you can learn
to keep your joy, keep your happiness,
learn to keep your emotions regulated,
learn to keep your body grounded
in those situations,
and you can truly, not a fake way, feel
joy in the midst of the hardest
situations that are happening. You can
start to think more creatively. You can
come up with creative ideas.
what used to and would have broken you
will no longer have that power over you.
And so
this is one of the most number one areas
in business that you can learn to grow
in is that you can learn that what
happens to you around you. Situations
that you're in
no longer have the power to derail you,
pull you off track, destroy you
like they used to.
and redesigning and redeveloping your
life and even your personality to be
able to do that.
You know, personality is really just
memories that we play over and over and
over again that then influence
how we are in our way of being.
I got that from uh Dr. Dr. Joe Despensza
uh and I and I found that to be really
really powerful is that if you keep
thinking a certain way constantly
thinking thinking thinking this way that
will turn into behavior that then will
turn into a habit that then will turn
into a personality.
And so what we can do is we can shift in
that same way by adjusting our thinking
by adjusting what are we focused on?
What are we looking at?
And you'll be surprised the results that
happen from it. If you want to be
successful as a business owner, this is
an area to grow in to learn that listen,
stuff happens, situations happen. We
don't always feel the best. Sometimes we
want to cry. Lay on the couch. Sometimes
our health, we might feel like giving
up. Control what you can control.
Give yourself some time to feel it. And
then pull yourself back out of it.
Here's the truth. Nobody else is coming
to pull you out of it. Nobody else is
coming to save you. It's true. We might
be wanting that. We might be wanting
somebody else to come and save us. But
the truth is is that when you can pull
yourself out of the pit, you don't go to
your normal things that you might rely
on, you don't you don't go to drugs,
alcohol, pornography, scrolling social
media,
watching television, playing video games
as a way to escape.
But you learn to feel
the tough feelings.
And then you learn to look and say,
"Okay, what can I learn from this? How
can I grow in this? How can I become
stronger to handle what used to have
broken me?" And this applies to your
campaigns for your Facebook ads. This
applies to the technology in your
business. You might like if you get
emotionally stuck because you are
struggling with how the technology in
your business is not working how you
want it to or things are broken or a
campaign isn't working or how other
people are responding or people not
showing up for you or things like that.
Whatever those situations are that
you're dealing with,
if you can learn to be stronger in the
midst of those situations, you can
accomplish anything you imagined as a
business owner, as a mentor, as a
service provider.
And listen, yeah, sometimes we need to
work with a therapist through what is
the underlying issue beneath the surface
that's causing this to keep coming up.
dealing with some of those issues.
Listen, I believe that you can
accomplish anything you set your mind
to.
But as a business owner, sometimes we
got to change the behavior of what we
normally do, the cycles that happen,
those cycles, so that when things don't
go how we want them to, we see it as a
positive.
And that will help you tremendously.
Listen, if you're a coach, mentor,
trainer, and you want to get help in
your business, I'd love to help you. I'd
love to come alongside you, guide you,
direct you, have you join my Wealthy
Coach Academy program.
You can go check it out, one of the
links below or over my website at
jeremiacowski.com.
We'll talk soon, everybody. Have a good
one.
[Music]
[Applause]